so let's look at an example of
fabrication costs suppose that the cost
of manufacturing a wafer is $5,000 so we
pay five thousand dollars to manufacture
a whole wafer and cut it up into chips
let's consider what happens when we have
some really small chips so that we can
fit 400 of them on a wafer and then we
want to manufacture large ships that are
four times the size of the small chip so
now you would think that we would have
100 of those on a wafer but because the
wafer is round and the chips are square
we lose some chips along the edge so
let's say that we can fit only 96 of
these large chips on a wafer and finally
we will consider huge ships that are 4
times again so they're four times the
size of the large ship and then 24 of
them would be 1/4 of this but because
again the wafer is round and the chip is
square we lose some more along the edges
so let's say only 20 of them can fit on
a wafer and let us also suppose that
there are 10 defects on each wafer what
we want to compute is what's the
manufacturing cost of a small large and
huge chip the chip cost will be the
$5,000 for a wafer divided by how many
good chips we get per wafer so now for
our small chips what we get is that the
cost is equal to $5,000 divided by we
have 400 chips on a wafer but we lose
Stan to defects so we really have $5,000
for 390 chips and that gives us a cost
of 12 dollars and 80 cents to
manufacture a working chip for a large
ship we get the cost to be $5,000
divided by 96 of them fit on a chip but
again these defects are gonna be on the
wafer and they will affect 10 of our
chips so we lose them to defects so we
end up with paying $5,000 for
manufacturing and
get only 86 working chips so we get 50
$8.20 as the cost of our chips so note
that the chip is only four times the
size of a small chip but the cost is
about five times the cost of a smaller
chip and finally for a huge ship the
cost is going to be $5000 we get only 20
chips fabricated and now there are 10
defects on a wafer but with chips this
big it seems likely that maybe two of
these defects are gonna end up on the
same chip so instead of losing ten ships
to the effects because each defect
affects a whole chip let's say that we
only lose nine chips because of these
defects so we pay five thousand dollars
and manufacture only eleven chips that
work this is much more than four times
the cost of a large chip this means
really that if we are fabricating chips
that are really large
any slight increase or decrease in chip
size is going to significantly change
the cost we have seen that here the
difference was five times instead of
four here the difference is almost ten
times instead of four so if this is what
manufacturing costs look like and if we
combine this with what Moore's law gives
us which is we can fit more stuff on the
same chip we really have two choices
when we get a generation of Moore's law
to play for us one we can have a smaller
chip that does exactly the same things
that a larger chip could do previously
because now we can make things smaller
and as you can see getting takes smaller
gives us much lower cost so one way of
benefiting from Moore's law is to
getting smaller and thus a lot cheaper
than before while keeping the same
functionality the other way of
benefiting from Moore's law is to build
something new that has the same area as
the old thing and that means that we get
something faster and more capable for
the same cost that the old thing had so
if we are interested in high performance
processors typically we will do
but if we are interested in doing
something that could not be done before
then this is what we usually benefit
from take a cell phone for example early
on what we wanted to put in a cell phone
could not be very smart so we had non
smart phones eventually the processor
that would be required to make a smart
phone became small enough to put in a
cell phone and also cheap enough so that
we can afford it and that's when we
started having cell phones similar
things occurred with digital watches and
all sorts of things we're basically
eventually what we want will fit in
where we want it it's just a matter of
how long do we need to wait for it
because of this because whatever
functionality we need will eventually be
cheap enough and small enough to fit